<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chris Tomy</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on Chris Tomy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cyberchris.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experiment with Boids with Blazor</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/blazor-boids/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/blazor-boids/</guid><description>I built a boid simulation with Blazor that allows you to toggle the three rules, as well some other options. Check it out here.
Notably, you can switch between rendering in JS, or through Blazor&amp;rsquo;s API, with significant performance effects. (Spoilers: JS is way faster.)</description></item><item><title>NudgeMe: Cross-Platform Mobile Wellbeing Tracker</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/nudgeme/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/nudgeme/</guid><description>This was a fairly extensive project undertaken as part of one of my modules, and although I don&amp;rsquo;t usually mention university work in Showcase, this is an exception since everything we did was self-learned.
I was team leader for a team of two (including me), and we built a full-stack cross-platform mobile application designed to help the UK population track and share their wellbeing &amp;amp; steps. The mobile client was built with Flutter and the back-end in Go.</description></item><item><title>Basic Scripting With Awk And Gnuplot</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/awk-and-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/awk-and-gnuplot/</guid><description>Posted to HN. Comments and discussion highly encouraged.
Introduction This will be a short example-based guide to (a) awk (b) gnuplot and (c) using them in a script.
I needed to graph some data based on the output of a command run a couple times. So what better way to solve that five minute task than to spend an hour learning awk &amp;amp; gnuplot to automate it?</description></item><item><title>Adding an iCalendar source to Calfw (feat. Doom Emacs)</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/ical-doom-emacs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/ical-doom-emacs/</guid><description>Here&amp;#39;s my calendar in Emacs. I use both an org-agenda and an iCalendar source. Introduction This will be a short post on how I use custom sources for the Doom Emacs calendar module; in particular, a iCalendar/ics source.
Whenever I mention &amp;#39;Doom&amp;#39;, I&amp;#39;m referring to Doom Emacs.
Prerequisites A basic understanding of how to use Doom Emacs, and some familiarity with Lisp-like languages.</description></item><item><title>GSA Ultra Hackathon</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/gsa-ultra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/gsa-ultra/</guid><description>Thanks to GSA Capital for sending me these cool t-shirts for my standing in their recent hackathon. I placed 109 out of over 900 undergrads/postgrads worldwide. Congrats to the winners!</description></item><item><title>CLI Case Converter</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/case-converter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/case-converter/</guid><description>case-converter is a free and open-source command-line application to convert the case of matched sections of text into other cases. It&amp;rsquo;s a convenient alternative to using a sed script.
I coded it in a day mostly to learn how to properly write modern (at the time of writing) Python applications, using Poetry and pytest.</description></item><item><title>Writing Assignments with Org-mode (in Doom Emacs)</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/org-mode-assignments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/org-mode-assignments/</guid><description>Introduction This post will be a brief tour on writing (work/university) assignments in org-mode, with the goal of producing a nicely typesetted PDF document without having to use much LaTeX.
Everything mentioned will also apply to Emacs in general, but Doom Emacs comes with all the features I mention.
Prerequisites Basic knowledge of org-mode, LaTeX (if math required), and Emacs.
(Very) Quick Org-Mode Primer Org-mode is a plain-text hierarchical markup language.</description></item><item><title>CLI Youtube Searcher</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/searchtube-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/searchtube-setup/</guid><description>This was an older writeup of mine that I posted before I had set up this blog. I am reposting it for my blog now.
What&amp;rsquo;s this for? After stumbling upon the youtube-dl program (link to the repo), I was impressed with its functionality but found it quite inconvenient to have to leave the terminal to search for the url. This led me to write this python script that lets you search Youtube and display the video/playlist ID, all in the command line.</description></item><item><title>CLI Youtube Searcher</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/cliyoutube/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/cliyoutube/</guid><description>Have a look at my blog post.</description></item><item><title>Local Music Playback Skill for MycroftAI</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/mycroftai-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/showcase/mycroftai-music/</guid><description>A skill/extension for the MycroftAI assistant that allows playback of downloaded mp3 files with MycroftAI (on Linux).
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code.</description></item></channel></rss>