<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emacs on Chris Tomy</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/tags/emacs/</link><description>Recent content in emacs on Chris Tomy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cyberchris.xyz/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding an iCalendar source to Calfw (feat. Doom Emacs)</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/ical-doom-emacs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/ical-doom-emacs/</guid><description>Here&amp;#39;s my calendar in Emacs. I use both an org-agenda and an iCalendar source. Introduction This will be a short post on how I use custom sources for the Doom Emacs calendar module; in particular, a iCalendar/ics source.
Whenever I mention &amp;#39;Doom&amp;#39;, I&amp;#39;m referring to Doom Emacs.
Prerequisites A basic understanding of how to use Doom Emacs, and some familiarity with Lisp-like languages.</description></item><item><title>Writing Assignments with Org-mode (in Doom Emacs)</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/org-mode-assignments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/org-mode-assignments/</guid><description>Introduction This post will be a brief tour on writing (work/university) assignments in org-mode, with the goal of producing a nicely typesetted PDF document without having to use much LaTeX.
Everything mentioned will also apply to Emacs in general, but Doom Emacs comes with all the features I mention.
Prerequisites Basic knowledge of org-mode, LaTeX (if math required), and Emacs.
(Very) Quick Org-Mode Primer Org-mode is a plain-text hierarchical markup language.</description></item><item><title>Day/Night Theme Switching on Doom Emacs (+ Bonus Config)</title><link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/doom-emacs-custom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/doom-emacs-custom/</guid><description>Intro So, inevitably, as one delves deeper into their editor of choice, one finds themselves wishing to customise it to some extent.
Vim can handle this sufficiently, but I found myself reaching the point where my vim config started to get a little bit cluttered. So, after having a look at Emacs, I decided to make the switch, courtesy of Doom Emacs.
The init.el file in the private config already handles most of the configuration you&amp;rsquo;d want to get started with, but there were two things I added to my config.</description></item></channel></rss>